Travis Holt



travisgholt@outlook.com



linkedin.com/in/travisgholt



206-637-0638



https://github.com/travisgholtsr

Summary

UiUx

UiUx Designer with 12 years working as a top producer of happy clients, killer ideas, and deliverables that are on scope and in time via the art team in multiple ad agencies. He has helped launch over 400 apps, websites, brands, startups and other businesses as the art director, marketing director and/or lead design - developer.

SEO

A specialist in SEO (Search Engine Optimization), industry leading producer, with over10 years experience, 100+ clients gaining top 10 ranking in over 1 Million keywords and a 100% targeted keyword success ratio.

Art

As a street artist he has not neglected a pursuit of his lifelong passion in art and the community philanthropy efforts which help artists become self sufficient financially and help fund public art projects.

Experience



Marketing Director

Vulcan Ad Agency

Sep 2008 - Present (12 years 8 months +)

Available for contacting or freelance work for consultation of business or brands that would like to cut costs and make a more efficient way to get better results. Websites, apps, automation, testing, data science and marketing from all channels.



Art Director

Upward Internet Marketing, LLC

Jan 2014 - Oct 2016 (2 years 10 months)

I was the highest ranking executive in Upward Internet Marketing, LLC until I broke my neck in a diving accident and had to close the business shortly after we had opened on a shoestring budget. My main responsibilities include developing and implementing high-level strategies, making major corporate decisions, managing the overall operations and resources of a company, and acting as the main point of communication between the board of directors and the corporate operations. We focused on automation and business efficiency via business dashboard, web apps, api integrations, SEO and PPC efforts that lead into a drip campaigns where automated delivery of ads resulted in an average of 2700% return on investment for our clients.



SEO Specialist

Summerwinds BIS, LLC

Jun 2015 - Feb 2016 (9 months)

In charge of conversion rates, organic search rankings, PPC campaigns, analytics and reporting, traffic and online lead generation. Eliminated bloat in the marketing budget which was at 75% at my time

of hire and then increased the ad spend to over 10x the initial budget to account for over 80 sales per month with a value of over \$9m. The VPG (average value per tour) for these inbound sales were staggering way above the industry average of \$220 to \$3950. I made advertisements, landing pages, optimization of websites, developed many web presences, created events and PR campaigns to deliver SEO results by becoming a top influencer in the market. On my departure I had just finished building in my free time a travel app that changed how people would purchase travel and completed the development after my contract ended for fun at home.

The Gorilla Ad Agency

Nov 2008 - Dec 2015 (7 years 2 months)

My divorce was the end of the amazing career I had for the company of which I handled the art and project management side of the business. We serviced over 400 clients in that time and had zero complaints or unhappy customers. My SEO capabilities brought the website we had into over 700 cities with top 5 ranking by creating optimized landing pages to target the top 800 in the USA. I had acquired clients all over the globe from Afghanistan, UK, Mexico, India, Russia and in nearly every state in the USA. The clients from this company are still calling me for help from time to time as our company offered an amazing service at super affordable rates with on time deliverables. We ended up becoming a white label provider of ad agency services for dozens of advertising and marketing companies all over the country by positioning ourselves as a the in-house marketing department that worked remotely. Not one project was outsourced and we had over 100+ 5 star reviews in the freelance website Guru.com.

Internet Marketing Manager

Tripium, Inc.

Jun 2014 - Jun 2015 (1 year 1 month)

In charge of internet marketing for iBranson.com and other Tripium entities. Including social media, web design, SEO, PPC, email marketing and more. The duties I was responsible for were to redevelop a website within 2 months which was in production overseas for 2 years and already costing the company \$20k+ without ever launching. I made video reels for promotions, created content, delivered landing pages and developed the strategy to market the business for the next year. I left when my contract expired and decided to move into a different opportunity.



VP of Marketing

Macarthur Strategies

Jan 2006 - Oct 2008 (2 years 10 months)

Managed the marketing team & the sales force. Created a strategy to increase the overall marketing efforts, reach our new client acquisition goals and trained the staff in sales and customer service. Studied to get my Series 7 and 22 before the company troubles with the book keeping in a fund and I decided to find another place to work. I was responsible for over a \$1m increase in revenues and trimmed costs down by making less people more effective rather than having 20 brokers we kept 5 and tripled production.

Education



Les Seattle Central College

Associate's degree, Business Administration and Management, General 1996 - 1998

Skills

Web Design • Web Development • SEO • graphic design • Website Development • Google Website Optimizer • Google Webmaster Tools • Media Planning • Media Buying • Social Media Marketing